Stanton A. Coblentz Papers
Stanton A. Coblentz Papers
1933-1971
Coblentz, Stanton A. (Stanton Arthur), 1896-1982.
5 linear ft.
American author, novelist, poet, editor of literary periodical, Wings. Collection includes manuscript poems, book manuscripts and galley proofs, articles, and photographs.
149735
Biographical History
Stanton Arthur Coblentz (1896-1982) was an American author, novelist, poet, and the editor of the literary periodical Wings
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Stanton A. Coblentz Papers contains manuscript poems, book manuscripts and galley proofs, articles, and photographs. The collection consists of two separate accessions which have not been integrated. The accession is indicated by a date in parenthesis following the series title, for example: Correspondence (1978).
The 1966 accession contains biographical material, one photograph, and manuscripts of books of epic poems and prose.
The 1978 accession contains correspondence as well as galleys, typescripts and published editions of several of Coblentz's books.
Because the two accessions contain duplicate box numbers, please indicate accession and box number when requesting an item.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material within each series is arranged alphabetically by title. Published issues of Wings are arranged chronologically.
Separated Material
Published editions of Coblentz's books have been transferred to Rare Books for cataloging. Please refer to to locate these items (search on "Gift of Stanton A. Coblentz").
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Fiction; Literature -- American Poetry; Science fiction; Coblentz, Stanton A. (Stanton Arthur), 1896-1982.; Authors, American.; Novelists, American.; Periodical editors -- United States.; Poets, American.; Articles.; Galley proofs.; Manuscripts for publication.; Photographs.; Poems.; Authors.; Novelists.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Biographical material (1966)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Subject files (1966)
  - Photographs of Coblentz (Box 1)
- Manuscripts (1966)
  - Epic poems
    - Atlantis (Box 1)
    - Pageant of the New World, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Prose
    - The Blue Barbarians, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - From Arrow to Atom Bomb, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - New Poetic Lamps for Old (Box 2)
    - Next Door to the Sun, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - The Runaway World, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - The Swallowing Wilderness, 2 folders (Box 3)
    - A World Without Water, 2 folders (Box 3)
- Published material (1966)
  - Articles by Coblentz (Box 4)
  - Wings, edited by Coblentz, 1939-1960; incomplete; lacking 1940, 1944-1946, 1948, 1953; 11 folders (Box 4)
- Correspondence (1978)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960 (Box 1)
- Writings (1978)
  - Galleys
    - Ten Crises in Civilization, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Typescripts
    - After 12,000 Years, 1950; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - The Challenge to Man's Survival, 1971; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - The Long Road to Humanity, 1959; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - The Madman from the Eastern Isles, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - The Pageant of the New World, 1968; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Ten Crises in Civilization, 1965 (Box 1)
    - When the Birds Fly South, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Published material
    - Pamphlets, 1943-1971 (Box 1)
    - Books, Transferred to Rare Books for cataloging.
    - Magazines
      - Wings, 1933-1958; 68 issues (Box 3)